

Kasun Lakshitha Amarasinghe

OBJECTIVE

As an Engineer with 3+ years of IT experience, I work for Cognite AS, an Oslo-based global industrial AI SAAS provider that provides digitalized solutions to leading global companies in industries such as oil and gas, shipping, manufacturing, and power. Extensive knowledge of machine learning, data engineering, and cloud platforms, as well as Python, Azure, Docker, and Kubernetes.

CONTACT





116-C, Amarawansha Street, Meetiyagoda, Sri Lanka



+9471 6994785



kasunlakshitha418@gmail.com



https://linkedin.com/in/kasun-lakshitha-07103b13b



https://github.com/lakshitha94

Experience

03/2020 - Present

Software Engineer Creative Software Technologies, Sri Lanka Vender as Cognite AS

As a member of a global product team by developing, managing, and maintaining customer-specific cloud-based solutions to ensure their reliability and availability. Providing technical support and further optimizations based on customer requirements for cloud-based solutions delivered by R&D teams to the world's leading gas and oil companies.

- Support and develop solutions for a Norwegian client company that provides digital infrastructure for the oil and gas industry.
- Developed customized ETL pipelines, monitoring end-to-end processes and fixing bugs.
- Worked on Docker images and deploy them into Kubernetes.
- Accessed Data from the cloud, and developed new models. And deployed the into the cloud service.
- Setting up Azure AD and managing access through the AD for large organizations. (Azure tenants)
- Performed Major incident handling for a SaaS Product.
- Setting up Prometheus push gateways and matrices for monitoring purposes.
- Performed monitoring for SaaS product by using Google Bigquery, Stackdriver logs, and setting up Grafana dashboards as well as light step matrices.

08/2019 - 02/2020

Data Science Intern Creative Software Technologies, Sri Lanka Vender as Cognite AS

Worked as a member of a team at Creative Technology Solutions (PVT) Ltd. It is a platform that provides insights into the data generated by IoT devices, primarily in the Oil and Gas industry.

Projects involved:

 Chalk influx - A project is done to forecast the possibility of a failure in an oil extraction machine using time series.
 Technologies used: Python / Machine learning

Tools & Technologies

- Data Engineering
- Machine Learning
- API management
- Python / OpenCV
- Azure
- Model Hosting
- Docker/ Kubernetes
- Prometheus/ VictoriaMetrices
- Grafana/PlotlyDash
- SQL and NOSQL Database Systems

PROJECTS

USA Shoe Market Analysis- Using Python

(08/2018-11/2018)

Project done for Stax.Inc, Colombo

- Extracting Function from Figures Extracting Functions from printed figures in documents by digitizing them.
 - Technologies used: Python / OpenCV / AWS
- worked for an internal R&D project related to theft detection using CCTV videos.

Technologies used: Azure / ReactJs

EDUCATION

2016 - 2020

Department of Statistics Faculty of Science, University of Colombo

B.Sc. in Applied Statistics (GPA 3.2)

ORGANIZATIONS

AIESEC in Sri Lanka (02/2018 – 03/2019)

Team Member of Be a Sri Lankan Project, IGV Department, Colombo Central

CERTIFICATIONS

- Azure data fundamentals
- Introduction to Cybersecurity Cisco
- Machine Learning Coursera
- Hadoop Platform and Application Framework Coursera
- AWS Fundamentals: Going Cloud Native Coursera

RESEARCH

Extracting Functions from figures in documents

Extract data from graphs on paper as material before digitize world exists.

Identify the spread range of X axis and Y axis of the graph and obtain the datapoint of the coordinates into a csv file.

GitHub: https://github.com/lakshitha94/Research

Jira sprint board data extractor

Every day at midnight, extract data from each issue in the board and export it to a big query and Google sheet via Google API, as well as to an AWS S3 bucket as a .csv file.

Technologies used: Python/ Docker/ Kubernetes/ GCP/ Azure/ AWS/

Incoming webhook
Execution type: CronJob

DECLARATION

I hereby certify that the above-mentioned information is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.